Liam McKenna - Software Engineer

Contact Information:

Phone: 083 444 8785 Email: liam.mckenna@outlook.ie

Address: Greystones, Wicklow

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/liammckennafullspec

Website: [TBA]

Introduction:

I am a Software Engineer with a background in graphic design and a special interest in bioinformatics and proteomics data management. Over the past two years, I have worked to develop and maintain an internal data warehouse and user interface, in collaboration with data scientists, while also refining UI/UX designs. I am currently studying System Information & Information Technology at DIT Dublin, alongside my full-time work, as part of my ongoing effort to deepen my practical knowledge in Software Design and Computer Science.

Skills and Recent Tools:

Frontend	Backend	CLI & Version Control	DevOps	Design & Tools	Modeling	Project Management
HTML, CSS,	Node,	Git,	Azure,	Photoshop,	UML/ERD's	Scrum,
JavaScript,	Express.JS,	GitHub,	AWS,	Illustrator,		Agile,
JSX, JSON,	Python,	GitLab,	Docker,	Figma,		Asana,
React,	Django, DRF,	Docker,	Firebase,	Premiere Pro,		User Stories,
Redux,	Anaconda,	WSL, Ubuntu,	Netlify,	VS Code,		Stakeholder
Framer Motion,	Postgresql,		Vercel,	Trello,		Management,
Next.Js,	SQL,			Datagrip,		Sprint Planning,
Chart.js				MongoDB, Atlas,		

Experience:

Software Engineer, Nuritas (Oct 2021 - Present)

- Developed and maintained an internal data warehouse and user interface.
- Worked closely with Data Science teams on API and logic function construction for machine learning models.
- Led UI/UX design efforts, implementing new designs into React.
- Used Docker and GitLab for development environments and version control.
- Started as Junior Developer, promoted after a year due to demonstrated skills and dedication.

Full Stack Web Developer, Full Spectrum (May 2021 - Oct 2021)

- Worked directly with clients on full stack website applications development.
- Primarily used MERN stack with React frontend and Node/Express backend. Databases focused on SQL or MongoDB.

Web Support Intern, Glowfox (Aug 2020 - Oct 2021)

Worked closely with B2B integration of the Glofox Web platform into the clients' dedicated websites.

• Acted as the first line of support for all web development queries.

Software Developer, Cloudtech Ltd (Jan 2020 - Feb 2021)

 Worked on custom software solutions, CRM setup & management, native & web development, project management & documentation.

1st & 2nd Ivl Tech Support, Hewlett Packard Enterprise (Jun 2018 - Jan 2020)

 Provided specialist IT support to first level agents, resolving major issues with clients' software and hardware.

Audio Visual Technician, Sonics Avi (Aug 2017 - Jun 2018)

Provided IT support to engineers and clients. Worked on building comms racks, hardware installation & setup, and cable crimping & running.

Graphic Designer & Media Manager, Sin Nightclub (May 2012 - Aug 2017)

 Had full creative control of the company with start-to-finish design projects, budget setting, cash flow management, club and event creation, and promotion and marketing.

Education:

Technology University Dublin (Sept 2018 - 2023)

• BSc in Information Tech & Information Systems (Hons)

Crumlin College (Sept 2017 - 2018)

• Certificate in Software Engineering